hello welcome to another video of C
snippet so this is basically the
continuation of last video where we are
looking into spring data jpa
relationships in the last video we have
already looked into what exactly is the
relationship and we have started looking
into the type of relationship and first
type you have already seen that is one
to one relationship rate and in this
video we are going to look into the rest
of the relationships so let's get
started without wasting any time so this
is going to be a fun video so sit back
relax and enjoy the show and let's jump
jum into the agenda so again we have
similar kind of agenda so we have seen
relationship between entities we have
seen type of relationships and we have
again seen one to one mapping over here
right now in this video we are going to
cover one to many many to one and many
to many mappings so in the last video we
have seen applicant and resume entities
in this video we will add few more
entities to it in order to look into
this particular mappings one to many
many to one and many to many right let's
get started and look into one to many
and many to one mapping over here right
so now our applicant and resume have
one-on-one mapping right now what we
need over here is we may need another
entity so that our applicant and that
particular entity may have one to many
mapping right we have applicant we have
resume now let's say we have application
table right we have application entity
so our one applicant can apply for
multiple applications right so there may
be multiple application open so your
applicant May apply for multiple
application so he have multiple
applications now right that is one
applicant to many applications mapping
right what I will do over here let me
just add applications table so there we
go we have added this applications table
where we have ID status position
applicant ID right applicant ID is
basically foreign key and uh which is a
ID inside your applicant table so one
applicant can have many applications now
so let's give that kind of mapping over
here so there we go so your one
applicant can have
many applications right so means one to
star star means many right so that means
one to many mapping right so it is one
to many mapping over here so one means
one star means many right so that's how
we read our entity relationship diagram
right without wasting any time let's
quickly implement this right so what I
will do over here I will go back to our
editor and what I will do I'll create a
new entity Java class let's say
application and I will mark it as a
entity and what I will do I will add few
Fields over here so I have first added
ID status and position what else we
added over here ID status position and
applicant ID right so I will create
object of applicant so it will be pretty
similar to how we created inside resum
so what I will do I will just copy this
the entire thing probably and uh I will
paste it over here and I will remove all
these things and we will write it from
the scratch now right so we know that
this is going to be one to many mapping
right so we'll just mark it as one to
many let me go back over here and here
what I will do I will add so I have
created this field which is applications
right because each applicant can have
multiple applications that's why it is
list and in this case it will be one too
many mapping one too many right in this
case it will be one too many mapping
because we have one applicant and many
application right but in the other case
in the application when we look into
application
is one to many correct that is a
question is one too many correct so
let's go back to our diagram over here
now if you see into applicant we have
one applicant with many applications
right so that is correct but when we
look into applications we have many
applications which can be Associated to
one applicant rate because this guy is
applying for many applications so we
have we can have many applications which
is associated with one applicant so if
you see we have star one over here so it
should be many to one mapping then we
look at this angle right so it is many
to one for applicant it is one to many
right but for applications it is many to
one for applicants it is one applicant
can apply for many jobs but but many
applications can be associated with one
job right it is kind of confusing but if
you understand it it is very
straightforward right when we add
Association inside applicants it should
be many to one right so if we go back
over here then it should not be one too
many rather it should be many to one and
again one more thing we can add is the
application ID which is join column over
here so that's it basically so now what
I will do I will just create a getter
and Setter quickly what I'll do I'll go
to getter Setter I'll select all and
I'll say okay that should create all the
C seter for us now what I'll do I'll
just add this boiler plate code over
here which is resum a controller service
and repository right I've have added
this particular application repository
where again I'm extending with jpa
repository nothing new that I have added
application service which will store our
application after that I have added
application controller which will store
our application dat now what I will do
I'll just run this code let's see what
happens right so let it come up so that
should be it now what I will do I'll
just add this application API over here
and I will just modify the body
accordingly so let me create it quickly
if I go to application we have status
and position right but now this
application is for which particular
applicant right so that we are not
defining over here right what we need to
give we need to give applicant ID over
here as well so I have modified this API
accordingly so what I will do I I will
accept applicant ID as well over here
and pass it to save application and here
first we will get applicant by using
that application ID and we will set it
to this particular application and after
that we will save right okay the app is
started now so what we can do over here
we can first add our applicant right so
let me just add applicant we have added
applicant now so what I will do I will
go back to this particular applications
and I will pass that applicant ID over
here and if I send it now then you will
see that we have this particular ID we
have developer position so this is
basically the application template that
we have and we have our applicant and
within that applicant we also have
resume right that is basically how it is
working now and we also have added one
too many mapping over here as well right
inside applicant we have added one too
many mapping for this particular
application so let's complete it now
I'll quickly add mapped by we'll say
applicant right and we will add cascet
type right so that everything will be
cascaded properly right so now what we
need to do is first we need to rerun
this application and while we add our
applicant what we need to do we need to
add our list as well right our list as
well we need to add now and what is the
name of that list applications right so
applications and we need a list so
applications and we need a list in this
case so what we we will have first so we
will only add one application for now
and in that application we have two
things right so the things which we have
added over here so what I will do I'll
just copy it I will paste it over here
instead paste it over
here and let me just beautify that a bit
so it should look good right so now we
have applications over here as well now
if I send it and again we are facing
same problem what problem we are not
getting it in the output rate why we are
not getting because we we have not added
get and Setter over here right what I
will do I'll say command n I'll go to
getter Setters and I will add this
getter and Setter and let's rerun this
code so that is running now and let's
send
it again we got the error right again we
got the error so let's see what exactly
is the error again we are getting same
problem over here it is saying not null
property reference has a null transient
value so this time you know how to fix
this right so let's go back to our
applicant service and over here now we
need to map this to two things right so
what we'll do over here we will say
applicant.
getet applications right so I will just
get it in a local variable which will be
a list now we need to iterate through
each application in this applications
because we are now passing a list and
now we need to set this applicant to
each of the applications right so that
we are not getting any error right if
you see over here we have this nullable
fals right so each applicant should be
mapped before Saving right so that
should resolve the issue now let me just
stop and
rerun now are you forecasting another
problem so let me send it over here
again same problem right so we are
getting this infinite Loop that we got
the last time again you know how to fix
that so here you need to add a Json
ignore annotation once you do that and
rerun this code and send this back again
now you're are getting it just fine
right right it is working properly now
right so all well and good so that is
basically our one to many and many to
one mapping over here right so we have
seen these two as well so let's go back
over here so one to many and many to one
we have seen right it's basically Vice
over Versa right so this is one to many
or many to one like that right so let's
move to the last one now that is many to
many right so this is basically
interesting now right so we will learn
few new things over here right let's go
back over here and again in order to
Define many to many relationships we
need to add one more entity right so
let's add one more entity for example
let me add one for example let's say we
have job right so let's say there is a
job and many applicants can apply for
that job right there is some kind of job
opening and many applicants can apply
for that job right and on the other hand
there could be many jobs and applicant
can apply for many jobs right again one
applicant can apply for many jobs and
one job can be applied by many
applicants right so it is many to many
mapping right now how we can Define that
over here let me just add that quickly
so there we go now we have applicant so
many applicant can apply for many jobs
or many jobs can be applied by many
applicants right so that is kind of a
many to many mapping between applicants
and job right now let's see how we can
implement this right so implementing
this is bit of a tricky thing right now
here how can we do this right so let's
say there there is this job right now
that job can have many applicants so it
will be kind of a list right and let's
say this applicant so this applicant can
apply for many jobs so that again will
be list right and mostly when it comes
to many to many mapping it is advisable
to create a separate table where we can
store the applicant ID and job ID right
so that table will look something like
this where we have applicant ID and job
ID that means applicant one have applied
to one 1 job applicant one have applied
to 102 as well and there is applicant 2
who is again applied for 101 so 101 have
two applicants it can be duplicate
Fields here as well duplicate Fields
here as well right that is something new
which we are going to look into over
here now let me quickly add a job entity
over here so let's go back to code and
what I will do I'll add a job entity so
there we go I have added it if you see
over here in the job I'm adding a many
to many mapping between these jobs and
this particular applicant this will
basically be the list of applicants but
it will be mapped somewhere else so we
will see how we can do that so what we
can do while we are adding it inside our
applicant so here what I will do I'll
add a new list of jobs now because
applicant can have list of jobs so first
thing we will do is many to many mapping
right many to many mapping and after
that we need to make use of at theate
join table why join table now because we
want to create some kind of other table
as we mentioned mentioned over here
right the other table will be let's say
something like this which will have
applicant ID and job ID
right so we will say join table and
we'll give some name to that table what
will be the name let's say
applicant jobs right after that we will
give join column to join this particular
applicant ID and after that we will give
inverse join columns which is basically
the job ID which is coming from job
right this table will have two fields
which is applicant ID and job ID right
this is basically the name this is
basically the column which is
referencing to applicant and this is
referencing to your job right so that is
how we Define it right now let me
quickly add a job repository over here
so that will add it for us again simple
stuff so this time we will create this
Getters and Setters upfront so that we
don't get that particular error what I
will do I'll create it and here also
Inside Job what I will do I'll create
Getters and Setters right so there we go
so for all of them we'll create in this
case now here I have added this
particular job repository again simple
stuff after that I have added a job
service where I'm injecting job
repository and applicant repository here
I'm just using making use of create job
and it will just save the job after that
we have ADD job to applicant right now
so what we'll do we'll get applicant ID
and job ID so what we will do we will
add this particular applicant to this
particular job right right so first we
will create applicant and job separately
then we will assign this particular
applicant to this job right and we have
respective job controller as well so
here we have a controller to create a
job and here what we have we have ADD
job to applicant API as well and we have
few other get apis as well right so what
I will do I'll run this application stop
and rerun and I will go to our postmen
and let's add applicant first oh it
should be started by now so let me add
applicant so that will add applicant for
us but if you see over here we have jobs
empty because this guy is not applied to
any job yet now we'll create another API
let me just duplicate this tab and what
I will do I'll create a job now so in
job controller I'll say API SL jobs and
we need to create right so we need to
pass a request body so what is there
inside our request body title and
description right so what I will do I'll
go to this particular body and I will
update this body to something like this
right so title and description now if we
send it we have created a job as well
but this job do not have applicants now
so we need to make use of other API that
we have over here I'll again duplicate
this so this time we don't need any body
and what is our API to map our job to
our applicant so let's go back to our
job controller and we have this one
right what I will do I'll just add it
here and now what we need we need couple
of parameters right so so as we are
getting parameters over here applicant
ID and job ID right what I'll do I'll
just copy applicant ID I'll give
applicant ID as one and I will copy job
ID as well from here and give job ID as
one as well I hope that was one it is
one one right what I will do I will just
hit this and there we go again we are
getting it in infinite Loop so again we
need to add Json ignore I will go back
over here to job and I will say at
theate
yes and ignore right now I will go back
again and I will add this applicant I
will go over here and add our job and I
will again map this particular applicant
ID to job now if you see this particular
applicant ID is mapped to this
particular job right so that is how you
can implement it right and now if we go
back to our H2 console and if we see our
database again and look at our job table
then you see there is one job and if we
see applicant now and run this then we
have this particular mangalam shrinu and
Main highlight over here is this
particular table basically applicant
jobs so if we look into it then you'll
see one applicant is applied to one job
so this is basically the another table
that we have created from here if you
remember if we go back to this applicant
then here we have created it by
using join table right so this
particular applicant table is created
for us right right so that is basically
how many to many mapping works right
that is basically many to many mapping
for us right so again it will be
represented by star to star so it is
many to many right so we have seen this
many to many mapping as well right so we
have seen all type of mapping so I hope
you have Fair understanding of what are
relationships inside jpa if you
understand it clearly this is a very
very easy topic if you have any
questions let me know in the comment
section if you like the video hit the
like button don't forget to subscribe to
Cod snippet share this video with your
friends so that they are also aware of
jpa relationships that's it for this
video see you in the next video